Guide to the Charles Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
All of these activities took a tremendous toll on the President's time. Still, he managed to produce a number of scholarly articles and book reviews, and was constantly invited to deliver lectures at other institutions. He often spoke of the need to avoid the post-war mistakes which his own generation had made. In a widely-circulated article, entitled "Versailles in Perspective," Seymour advised against a single program or effort aimed at ending wartime suffering, redefining national boundaries, and establishing a new international organization. He felt that such matters should be separately dealt with. He warned, too, that any new league of nations would have to be built on the basis of public consensus aimed at removing the causes of war rather than be dedicated simply to the prevention of war.
Seymour was always a popular public speaker, and in his talks to clubs and graduating classes he found the opportunity to underline some of the moral, political, and educational issues of the times. Thus in one of his Baccalaureate addresses he said:
We have become so habituated to the ruthless use of force, to barbarous inhumanity, to the destruction of good faith, that we become numb or neutral when we face the issue of right against wrong...The danger is not that someone will try to interfere with our opinions. The danger is that we shall not take the trouble to have any opinions at all.
He warned universities not to become "ivory towers" isolated from the main currents of national thought: There is a difference [he said] between right and wrong which cannot be destroyed by any negativist philosophy...there is a distinction between the truth and the lie, between courage and cowardice, between moral initiative and cynical irresponsibility. We believe that it is part of our university experience to make the distinction and to give effect to it.
Seymour also argued for increased educational opportunities for the disadvantaged, for expanded non-Western studies, and for broader programs for adult education. He deplored the "witch hunts" of the early 1950's, particularly when they interfered with academic freedom.
Throughout this period Seymour also retained the title of Curator of the House Collection. Although assistants had been hired to do a great deal of the day-to-day work, President Seymour personally supervised the preliminary processing of this immense collection, approved potential researchers and their topics, and wrote extensive critiques of manuscripts submitted to him by graduate students and professional historians.
In 1950, having reached Yale's mandatory retirement age of 65, Charles Seymour stepped down from the Presidency. His achievements as President had been impressive. The massive building campaign which had taken place under President Angell had been followed by less dramatic but perhaps more significant types of development under his successor. There had been important innovations in the undergraduate curriculum, including inter-departmental divisions and independent study projects. The Sheffield Scientific School had been merged with Yale College, thereby ending an unnecessary duplication of resources. The faculty was strengthened and special research institutes were established. The student body doubled; faculty salaries were greatly improved; Yale's Alumni Fund gifts led the nation. Newspaper articles about Seymour almost always mentioned the fact that he looked like a university president. But the dignity and solemnity of his appearance were tempered by a warm and easy manner. Charles Seymour, whose heritage and career were so intimately linked with Yale, was perhaps the ultimate Yale Man. As he prepared to leave Woodbridge Hall for the last time, he received a typical (and genuine) token of esteem from a former classmate who wrote, "I view your retirement as the sunset of our generation."
Seymour looked forward to his retirement as an opportunity to return to the full-time study and teaching of history. "I plan to rub off some of the administrative rust and get back to writing," he told well-wishers over and over again. Unfortunately, ill health was to prevent him from being as active as he had hoped. Nevertheless, so long as he felt well, he continued to supervise activities at the House Collection; and he never turned down requests for help from other scholars. Occasionally he lectured in the History Department, and he contributed a number of articles, book reviews, and introductions to books. "The End of a Friendship," which appeared in August 1963 in American Heritage Magazine, was his last article and was based on a confidential interview Seymour had had with Colonel House back in 1937, shortly before the latter's death. In it Seymour related House's version of his mysterious break with Woodrow Wilson. House maintained that his relationship with Wilson had not been ended by an argument over issues at the Paris Peace Conference, but had instead been slowly undermined by the second Mrs. Wilson, by Admiral Grayson (Wilson's physician), and by Bernard Baruch.
Early in 1963 Seymour began editing the "diary letters" which he had written forty-five years before at the Paris Peace Conference. Though his health was rapidly failing, he organized the papers, wrote an introduction, and began the task of deleting irrelevant material and preparing explanatory footnotes. He did not complete the project, for he died on August 11, 1963.
Foreign Affairs (N.Y.); World War, 1914-1918; Austria -- History -- 1918-1938; Czechoslovakia -- History -- 1918-1938; Germany -- History -- 1918-1933; Hungary -- Population; Italy -- History -- 1914-1922; Romania -- History -- 1914-1944; United States -- Foreign relations; Yugoslavia -- History -- 1918-1945; Authors; Diplomats; Historians; Auchincloss, Gordon, 1886-1943; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937; Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946; Bartholomew, Marshall, 1885-1978; Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1879-1979; Bemis, Samuel Flagg, 1891-1973; Benedict, Roswell Alphonso, 1855-; Berstorff, Johann von; Blue, Linden S.; Bonsal, Stephen, 1865-1951; Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950; Davidson, John Welles; Davis, Walter Goodwin, 1885-1966; Day, Clive, 1871-1951; Denton, Frances B., 1871-1948; Dodd, William E. (William Edward), 1869-1940; Doob, Leonard W. (Leonard William), 1909-2000; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970; Dreier, Katherine S. (Katherine Sophie), 1877-1952; Dulles, Allen, 1893-1969; Epler, Percy H. (Percy Harold), 1872-; Farnam, Thomas Wells, 1877-1943; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945; Fay, Sidney Bradshaw, 1876-1967; Ferrell, Robert H., 1921-; Foster, J. T.; Frazier, Arthur H.; Furniss, Edgar S. (Edgar Stephenson), 1918-1966; Gabriel, Ralph Henry, 1890-1987; Geddes, Eric Campbell, Sir, 1875-1937; Gerard, James W. (James Watson), 1823-1900; Graves, Henry Solon, 1871-1951; Grey of Fallodon, Edward Grey, Viscount, 1862-1933; Griswold, Alfred Whitney, 1906-1963; Hewes, James Ellicott; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Holborn, Hajo, 1902-1969; Hooker, Richard, 1878-; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938; House, Loulie; Hudson, Manley O. (Manley Ottmer), 1886-1960; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955; Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1899-1977; Joerg, W. L. G. (Wolfgang Louis Gottfried), 1885-1952; Keogh, Andrew, 1869-1953; Langer, William L. (William Leonard), 1896-1977; Lansing, Robert, 1864-1928; Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1884-1968; Lingley, Charles Ramsdell, 1877-1934; Link, Arthur S. (Arthur Stanley), 1920-1998; Lothian, Philip Henry Kerr, Marquis of, 1882-1940; Lovett, Sidney, 1890-1979; Lutz, Ralph Haswell, 1886-1968; Mallory, Philip Rogers, 1885-1975; Mantoux, Mathilde; Matin, Laurence W.; Mayer, Arno J., 1926-; McIver, Robert Morrison, 1882-; Mendell, Clarence W. (Clarence Whittlesey), 1883-1970; Mezes, Sidney Edward, 1863-1931; Myers, Walter D. (Walter Dennis), 1882-1973; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971; Notestein, Wallace, 1878-1969; Olds, Irving Sands, 1887-; Pierson, George Wilson, 1904-1993; Pirenne, Henri, 1862-1935; Polk, Frank L. (Frank Lyon), 1871-1943; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937; Sarkissian, Arshag Ohan, 1905-; Schilling, Walter, 1896-; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Sizer, Theodore, 1892-1967; Stanley, Harold, 1885-1963; Viereck, George Sylvester, 1884-1962; Walworth, Arthur, 1903-2005; Wasson, R. Gordon (Robert Gordon), 1898-1986; Watkins, Royall R.; Watt, George W. (George William), 1878-; Willert, Arthur, Sir, 1882-1973; Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt, 1872-1961; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Wiseman, William, Sir, 1885-; Hadley family; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1908; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Officals and employees; Paris Peace Conference. United States Territorial Section ( 1919-1920. United States Territorial Section) -- 1919-1920
- Correspondence, 1912-(1918-1922)-1963; Series I; 7'4" (20 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into the following sections:
  General Correspondence (16 boxes)
  This section contains the bulk of the correspondence. It is arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent, by the name of the organization, or by topic. Within each folder the letters are arranged chronologically.
  Peace Conference Correspondence (1 box)
  This section consists of Charles Seymour's correspondence files from the Paris Peace Conference of 1919. The letters are arranged alphabetically. Within each folder the letters are arranged chronologically. Consult the folder title listings under General Correspondence for Seymour's later correspondence with a particular individual.
  Family Correspondence (3 boxes) [Family Correspondence has been removed to the Seymour Family Papers, MS 440 (consult an archivist for assistance)]
  This section consists of correspondence by members of Charles Seymour's family which was of a purely personal, family nature. It is divided into the letters of Charles Seymour's wife, son, and brother-in-law. Within each division the letters are arranged chronologically. Consult the folder title listings under General Correspondence for the correspondence of family members concerning non-family matters.
  Note: Consult folder title listings in Series VI: HOUSE COLLECTION/ADMINISTRATION for Seymour's correspondence as curator of the House Collection.
  - General Correspondence
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1920 November 1-24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      Letters To CS/From CS: 4/14
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1920 November 26-30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 11/4
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1920 December 1-5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 8/5
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1920 December 6-12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/12
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1920 December 13-27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1921 January 3-10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 9/11
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1921 January 11-22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 8/11
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1921 January 24-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 8/10
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1921 February 2-12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 9/8
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1921 February 15-28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 8/6
    - Academy of Music (Philadelphia) Lecture Series, 1921 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 4/4
    - Academy of Political Science (New York), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 11a)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 1/0
    - Ackerman, Carl W., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Adams, E. G., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 0/1
    - Adams, G. B., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13a)
    - Alderman, Edwin A., 1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Aldrich, Mac, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allen, Ann M., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 1/1
    - Allen, Carleton M., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Allen, Frederick W., 1923, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 3/7
    - Allen, Stanley, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 2/2
    - Allison, John, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Alofsin, Herman, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Altschul, Charles, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Altschul, Frank, 1950, 1955-1956, 1958, 1960-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/4
      See also: box 4, folder 193
    - Alumni Board
      See: box 16, folder 933
    - Alvord, Danforth Fletcher, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - America-Jugoslav Society, Inc., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - American Committee for Effective Foreign Policy, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - American Foreign Service Journal, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 6/5
    - American Geographical Society
      See: box 2, folder 106-107 box 2, folder 108
    - American Heritage, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 9/6
      See also: box 10, folder 622 box 14, folder 848-869
    - Andrews, Charles M., 1912, 1923, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 3/0
    - Andrews, Frank, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 3/2
    - Andrews, Forest Lee
      See: box 15, folder 879
    - Angel, Beth (Mrs. John), 1924
      Letters To CS/From CS: 0/8
      [Transferred to the Seymour Family Papers, MS 440]
    - Angell, James R., 1922-1923, 1926-1927, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 12/7
    - Angell, Kay (Mrs. James), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Anglo-American-Hellenic Bureau of Education, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 2/1
    - Annan, Noel G
      See: box 8, folder 474
    - Antiquarian and Landmarks Society, Inc.
      See: box 8, folder 471
    - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
      See: box 5, folder 301
    - Associated Press, 1923, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Atlantic Council, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 2/0
    - Atmore, Robert C.
      See: box 3, folder 151
    - Atterbury, Astelle (Mrs. Grosvenor)
      See: box 1, folder 39
    - Atterbury, Grosvenor, 1953, 1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Auchincloss, Edward H., 1950, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Auchincloss, Gordon, 1920, 1923, 1926-1928, 1938-1939, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      See also: box 7, folder 417
      See also: The Gordon Auchincloss Papers, MS 580
      See also: The Clive Day Papers, MS 173
      See also: The Inquiry Papers, MS 8
      See also: The Vance McCormick Papers, MS 478
    - Auchincloss, James C., 1950, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 4/2
      See also: box 3, folder 159-162
    - Auchincloss, Janet (Mrs. Gordon), 1943, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/5
      See also: box 5, folder 256
    - Avey, Albert E., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Babb, James T., 1949, 1952, 1954-1955, 1957, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 13/5
      See also: box 70, folder 56
    - Bahlman, Dudley, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bailey, Mrs., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Baker, Christina H., undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Baker, Newton D., 1921-1923, 1928, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/2
      See also: box 7, folder 378
    - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 6/7
      See also: box 15, folder 919
    - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1927, 1929, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 6/4
    - Bakhmetieff, Boris A., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Balfour, Arthur, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      See also: box 52, folder 262
    - Banks, Dick
      See: box 12, folder 774
    - Bannard, Otto T., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 0/2
    - Barber, Naomi A., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Barker Texas History Center, University of Texas
      See: box 15, folder 879-880
    - Barnes, Harry E., 1925, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 2/3
    - Barnette, Ralph, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Barnum, Earl M., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Barr, Stringfellow, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Barres, Herster, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Barrows, David N., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Bartholomew, Marshall, 1952, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Barton, Bruce, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Bausman, Frederick, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 1/3
    - Baxter, Elizabeth S., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Bayne, Hugh A., 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Beard, Charles A., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Beardsley, Harry S., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Belbe, Roderick, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Belin, G. d'A., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Belknap, William B., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Bell, Herbert C., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Bellinger, Alfred R., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Belmont, Eleanor R. (Mrs. August), 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/7
    - Bemant, Howard, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Bemis, Samuel F., 1951, 1953, 1958-1959, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 6/1
      See also: box 15, folder 875-877
    - Benedict, Roswell A., 1922, 1925, 1931, 1934, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/0
    - Benn Brothers, Publishers
      See: box 15, folder 885
    - Bennett, David, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Benson, W. S., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      See also: box 8, folder 483
    - Bentley, Dorothy A. (Mrs. Edward S.), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Benton, A. R.
    - Berger, George B., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Bergin, Thomas, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Bernstorff, Johann von, 1928-1929, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Bernstorff, Johann von, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 85)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 4/3
    - Bible, Howard W., 1938, 1943, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Bibliotheque de Documentation Contemporaine, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Biglow, Lucius H., 1950, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Bingham, Jonathan B., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Binkley, Robert C., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Bissell, Clifford, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Bissell, Willard S., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Blair, Edwin F. (Box 2, Folder 93)
      See also: box 16, folder 933
    - Blair, William, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Blanchard, Claude de, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Bliss, Harding, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Bliss, Tasker H. (Box 2, Folder 97)
      See also: box 1, folder 1-11
      See also: Books, "The Intimate Papers of Colonel House," boxes 21-43
      See also: box 52, folder 268
    - Blount, Frank
      See: box 16, folder 936
    - Blue, Linden S., 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Blum, John M., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 99)
      See also: box 7, folder 407
    - Boffey, David, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Bok, Edward K.
      See: box 1, folder 1-11
    - Bonsal, Stephen, 1928-1929, 1934, 1937, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 8/7
      See also: box 1, folder 27 box 2, folder 102
      See also: The Frances B. Denton Papers, MS 655
    - Bonsal's Reference to Lodge Compromise, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 102)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/9
    - Booth, Lewis S., undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Bowdoin College, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Bowen, Carroll G., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Bowman, Isaiah, 1920 January 6-12 (Box 2, Folder 106)
      See also: box 1, folder 1-11 box 4, folder 218
    - Bowman, Isaiah, 1920 January 30-Nov, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Bowman Memorial Lecture, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 108)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 4/1
    - Bracher, Vasa K., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Bradford, Arthur H., 1949-1950, 1952, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Branch, Robert D.
      See: box 3, folder 110
    - Breed, L. C., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Brewster, Eleanor, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Britton, Bessie S. (Mrs. John D.), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Bromer, Ralph S., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Bronson, Francis W.
      See: box 16, folder 935
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Brookline Country Club, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Brooks, Wendell S., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Brown, Arthur M., undated (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Brown, Marshall S., 1926 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Bryan, Mary B. (Mrs. William Jennings), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Bryce, Lady, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Buckler, William H., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 122)
      See also: The William H. Buckler Papers, MS 654
    - Budlong, Frederick G., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Buehrig, Edward H., 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 124)
      See also: box 8, folder 439
    - Bulkeley, Richard B., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 125)
      See also: box 3, folder 159-163
    - Bullard, Arthur, 1927, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 126)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 3/3
    - Bullitt, William C., 1930, 1942, 1953, 1956-1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 127)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 2/6
    - Bundy, Harvey, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Bunker, Raymond T., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Bunnell, Phil W., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Burnes, June
      See: box 3, folder 165
    - Burrowes, Hillier McC., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Bush, Prescott, 1950, 1954, 1956, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Bushnell, Sam, 1921, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray
      See: box 3, folder 176
    - Calder, Isabel M., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Calhoun, Robert L., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Cambridge Review, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Camp, T. J., [1950] (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Canby, Henry S.
      See: box 10, folder 598
    - Canfield, Cass
      See: box 7, folder 370
    - Carrington, Sarah, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Carter, Rev. Charles Francis, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 138a)
    - Carter, Frederick D., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Cassidy, R. A., 1927 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Castle, William R., 1952, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Catton, Bruce
      See: box 1, folder 28
    - Celantano, William C., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Chadbourne, Richard M., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Chalmers, Iris, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 144)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 4/0
    - Chamberlain, John R., 1935-1936, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Chance, Wade, 1928, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 7/4
    - Chapin, E. Barton, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Cheney, Howell, 1950, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Latané, J. H., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Chisholm, Hugh J., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Choate School, 1926, 1951, 1953, 1957, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Chudoba, Bohdan, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Clark, Charles E., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Clark, Charles U., 1926, 1956-1957, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 6/2
    - Clark, E. T.
      See: box 15, folder 899
    - Clark, Elias, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Clark, Loyal B., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Clark, Mrs. L. W., 1926 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Clark, Ralph E., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Class of 1903
      See: box 3, folder 109
    - Class of 1908, 1924, 1937, 1950, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 159)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 22/2
    - Class of 1908, 1957 April-July (Box 3, Folder 160)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 5/1
    - Class of 1908, 1957 August (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Class of 1908, 1957 September-November (Box 3, Folder 162)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 7/2
    - Class of 1908, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 163)
      Letters To CS/From CS: 6/3
    - Class of 1912, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 164)